<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on MYCOLab</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on MYCOLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi-mediated nitrogen transfer</title>
      <link>/project/plant_amf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/plant_amf/</guid>
      <description>Summary The goal of this project is to investigate how plant carbohydrates control arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi-mediated nitrogen transfer. Using isotopic labeling (13C and 15N) technology, we have shown that plant C limitation does not reduce N transfer from arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) to Plantago lanceolata. Instead, we have revealed greater N-for-C exchange efficiency between plant and AMF under plant C limitation (low CO2 concentration). C-limited host plants with AMF optimized the use of resources by increasing both C and N allocation to shoots to alleviate C limitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leguminous shrub encroachment and N transfer</title>
      <link>/project/shrub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/shrub/</guid>
      <description>Local study
We measured N concentrations and natural abundance 15N of shoot tissues from three dominant grasses from different plant functional groups across seven distances along a local transect (up to 500 cm) to the leguminous shrub, Caragana microphylla. Our results indicated the rhizomatous grass transferred fixed N over long distances while bunchgrasses did not. The presence of C. microphylla increased the shoot biomass of L. chinensis but decreased that of S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAstures and Climate Extreme (PACE)</title>
      <link>/project/pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pace/</guid>
      <description>Impacts of Rainfall and Temperature Extremes On Pasture Systems
Grasses and legumes are the primary foodstock for the meat and dairy industries, with an estimated value of more than $16.5 billion in cattle, sheep, wool, dairy and meat production (Australian Bureau of Statistics). The sustainable management of grazing systems depends on the availability of high-quality forage, year-round.
A key question facing the industry is how will predicted climate scenarios affect the productivity, quality and resilience of pasture systems in coming decades.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>